VETA, CHAN LOK YEE

veta.multimedia@gmail.com

 \bigcirc

Vancouver, Canada

linkedin.com/in/veta-chan/

SKILLS

Research

News Writing

Report Writing

Filming

Video editing

Video script writing

Adobe Premiere Pro

Adobe After Effects

Microsoft Outlook

Microsoft OneDrive

Microsoft Excel

Microsoft PowerPoint

Microsoft Word

Event Planning

Communication

Problem-solving

Decision-making

EDUCATION

MASTER IN IOURNALISM

University of Hong Kong 2018 - 2019

BSocSc in Asian and International Studies

City University of Hong Kong 2014 - 2018

LANGUAGES

ENGLISH - Native

Cantonese - Native

Mandarin - Proficient

SUMMARY

A flexible and detailed-oriented individual with over two years of experience in research and writing, managing assets and data, and a proven ability to effectively coordinate and collaborate with staffs at all levels and external partners. Extremely organized with the ability to work both independently of own initiative and as part of a successful team. Excels in fast-paced, deadline-driven and high-pressure environments while maintaining the highest of standards.

EXPERIENCE

CONTENT SPECIALIST

Doteasy Technology Inc., Vancouver, B.C. / August 2021 - Present

- Write guides and articles related to website building industry
- Build WordPress websites using Divi theme

ASSISTANT VIDEO PRODUCER

FORTUNE, Hong Kong / June 2020 - July 2021

- Produced 50+ editorial and event videos in a year
- In charge of conceptualizing, executing ideas, researching, video scripting, interviewing and producing short form explainer videos
- Video and Audio Editing, designed and created video background and motion graphics to deliver quality videos
- Assembled equipment before filming, including tripods, monitors, lighting, and audio recorders
- Assisted Executive Editor, Asia to manage programming, speaker recruitment, and follow-up communication for Eastworld Spotlight series
- Coordinated, collaborated and assisted event teams in U.S., China, and Hong Kong to arrange tapping and workflow
- Communicated with external partners and speakers to schedule meetings and technical checks for Fortune events
- Coordinated, liaised and supervised vendors for Fortune events
- Conceptualized, reported, and wrote news and feature stories for Fortune.com
- Managed video assets; created and maintained contact lists of expert and external partners

FREELANCE LOCAL REPORTER/PRODUCER

NBC, Hong Kong / June 2019 – December 2020

- Conceptualized, reported, and wrote articles for nbc.com
- Conducted social media monitoring, newsgathering, fact-checking, and translating official documents and press conferences
- Identified and booked guests for interviews, and arranged logistics for reporting trips (live broadcasting and documentary)

VIDEO ASSISTANT

Associated Press Television News, Hong Kong / March 2019 – June 2019

- Filmed, edited, wrote storyline and produced video packages for Associated Press clients
- Manage video assets; create and maintain contact lists of expert and external partners

